William Rubio

rubi.o@icloud.com | www.linkedin.com/in/guillermorubiobolger/ | +34 722 40 60 11

Bilingual in English and Spanish, I'm a tech-savvy and business-minded individual looking for exciting opportunities to utilize my skills and passion. From computer engineering to business, I've got a diverse academic background that I believe would be a valuable asset to any team. I'm always up for a challenge and I am confident in my ability to make a positive impact in a dynamic and fast-paced environment.

SKILLS

Languages: Bilingual in English / Spanish. United States Citizen.

Computer: Proficient in Java, C, Python, Assembly (RISC-V) and SQL, with knowledge of HTML, CSS for web development. Very experienced in all office applications and knowledgeable of some adobe programs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2021– present **El Corte Inglés** (Madrid, Spain)

Sales assistant, Cashier, and Replenishment

- Operated checkout lane quickly and accurately, utilizing retail equipment including a scale and barcode reader with end-of-day cash balancing responsibilities.
- Promoted sales of seasonal and discounted products in a courteous and friendly manner.
- Assisted floor staff with stocking and assisting guests.

2021–2022 Culver Academies (Indiana, USA)

Assistant Counselor – Tactical Officer

- Primary cadet developer and legal commander of the cadet company.
- Management of a company of 40 cadets. Responsible for their security, needs, mentoring, and ensuring they receive the full benefits of the Culver experience.
- Responsible for teaching sailing of the CMA RH Ledbetter, a 54-foot square rigger built in 1984, to more than 200 midshipmen.

EDUCATION

2020 – Present Charles III University of Madrid

Dual Bachelor's in Computer Science & Engineering, and Business Administration.

2023 – 2024 University of California

Dual Bachelor's in Computer Science & Engineering, and Business Administration.

 Accepted in the University of California Education Abroad Program to study for the 23-24 school year.

2018 – 2020 Zola School Villafranca

Baccalaureate specialized in Physics and Chemistry

- Graduated with honors, rendering free access to the first year of college in Spain.

Relevant coursework: Artificial Intelligence, Files and Databases, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Software Development, Algorithms and Data Structures, Software Engineering.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Interests: Water sports: rowing, sailing, swimming.

Certificates: TOEFL iBT, American Red Cross Lifeguard, Sailing Blue Book.

Additional education: Attended Culver Naval School, an Honour Naval School recognized by the US Navy. **Honors and awards:** Recipient of the Madrid Excellence Grant, a monetary grant given by the Community of Madrid to the best high school students who graduated in 2020. Recipient of the Santander Bank scholarship for non-European study abroad programs, given to the best students to receive a position in a foreign university.